# 福建，福州
Fuzhou, Fujian
# 我真的很难想象 在这么荒凉的地方
It's hard to believe that there is
# 能有一家很火爆的捞化店
a very popular "Lao hua" (rice noodle) restaurant in such a remote place
# 走吧 我们要去看一看
Let's go and take a look
# 这有多少种 好多呀
There are indeed a lot of kinds of food
# 但是海蛎和猪血是比较多的 只有海蛎和猪血是两盆
But oyster and pig blood curd are the major ones
(There are two bowls of each of them)
# 我说你这碗是面 还是要细粉 细粉
-Would you like noodles or thin rice noodles?
-Thin rice noodles, please
# 加猪血 海蛎
I'd like pig blood curd and oysters
# 罗汉肉吧
"Luo han rou" (Pork) as well
# 拿个香菇
And some mushrooms
# 在这里吃
Eat in?
# 对 在这儿吃
Yes
# 差不多了 可以
I think that's enough
# 35块钱 行
-35 yuan
-OK
# 细粉
Thin rice noodles
# 是你们的吗 细粉
Did you order thin rice noodles?
# 啊
Huh?
# 这么快吗 你吃哪一碗
-It's so fast!
-Which one is yours?
# 额 这个是什么 鱿鱼嘛
-Um, what is this?
-Squid
# 这个是鱿鱼 是（捞）面的
This one is noodles with squid
# 这个是米粉的
This one is rice noodles
# 谢谢 细粉
-Thank you!
-Thin rice noodles
# 有点烫 你还有盘菜
-It's hot
-Did you order a dish as well?
# 对 还有一盘菜
Yeah
# 这么快
It's so fast
# 难以想象这边的上菜速度 就是
It's amazing that they served so quickly
# 我刚坐下 然后阿姨就把两个碗拿过来了
The auntie brought the two bowls (of noodles) as soon as I took a seat
# 马上 青菜就上来了
Then the vegetable was served in no time
# 难以想象 这个上菜速度如此之快
It's just incredible that they served so fast
# 这一碗 你看 上面是料 下面是米粉
Look at this bowl
The ingredients are on the top while the rice noodles are at the bottom
# 足足的 35块钱
That's fully worthy of 35 yuan indeed
# 一个盆
A large bowl
# 量不算小吧
A large amount of food
# 捞化其实是捞米粉
"Lao hua" is actually "Lao" (slightly boil) rice noodles #从这里变得难以翻译了
# 捞的还是兴化的米粉
They use rice noodles from Xinghua
# 这种米粉原产于莆田
This kind of rice noodles originated from Putian
# 这个米粉有个特点就是
It's special because
# 放在汤水里 一捞就熟
it's ready to serve just after a dip in hot broth
# 时间长了呢 大家都会说 捞兴化粉
As time goes, people tend to say "Lao Xinghua fen"
# 再到后来就是捞兴化
Then "Lao Xinghua"
# 到现在就直接是 捞化
Now it simply becomes "Lao hua"
# 我还是第一次吃到这种口感的米粉
This is my first time to taste rice noodles with such a mouthfeel
# 米粉放在汤水里 一捞起来就熟了
The rice noodles are put in the broth and are instantly ready to eat
# 一咬就断了 而且还带有一种脆的口感
It's easy to cut in your mouth and gives you a crunchy feeling
# 你说咱们今天来吃捞化是来吃米粉的吗
You thought we came for "Lao hua" rice noodles today?
# 我觉得更多的是来吃这些配菜的
I would prefer to say that we came for the ingredients actually
# 捞的种类会很多
There are a lot of ingredients for the rice noodles
# 你看 刚才那一边
As you saw just now
# 摆了好多的肉 海鲜 贝类
There were various types of meat, such as
Seafood, shellfish
# 还有猪肉内脏
And pig offals
# 慢慢的都是（肉）
All types of meat
# 你如果说想吃
You can spend only 10 yuan on a meal
# 10块钱也行 上百块钱也是可以的
Or over 100 yuan if you wish
# 这碗捞化的灵魂在于这碗汤
The soul of the "Lao hua" (rice noodles) lies in the broth
# 有了这个汤之后 会让捞化更加鲜美
With the broth, the "Lao hua" is even tastier
# 捞化不仅可以捞米粉 还可以捞面
In addition to rice noodles, you can eat "Lao" wheat noodles as well
# 里面的料都是一样的
The ingredients are the same
# 不过是把米粉换成了面
while the rice noodles are replaced with wheat noodles
# 福建 石狮
Shishi, Fujian
# 20 块钱 20 块钱
20 yuan
# 加什么 只是加 加蛋 加海蛎
-What can we have?
-Eggs, oysters
# 那拿一份
I'd like one
# 打包？
To go?
# 在这儿吃 在这儿吃
Eat-in
# 里面坐 里面坐
Take a seat inside, please
# （后面坐着的）阿姨说 这个
The lady (sitting behind) said that
# 既可以叫海蛎煎 也可以叫蚝仔煎
This can either be called "Hai li jian" or "Hao zai jian" (oyster omelette)
# 它这个是先炒好海蛎
First, stir-fry the oysters
# 炒的差不多了 加上带蒜苗的地瓜粉
When the oysters are nearly done, add potato starch with garlic sprouts
# 最后呢 就是放上鸭蛋
Finally, add duck eggs
# 我们以前吃的海蛎煎就是煎的比较整一些
(Previous video) The "Hai li jian" we had before was cooked into a whole
# 像一个饼的形状
like a pancake
# 这个就是煎的比较散一些
This one is looser
# 口感上 也有一些的不同
There are some differences in terms of mouthfeel
# 原来的 吃的比较脆一些
The previous one was more crunchy
# 因为形成了一个饼的形状嘛
Because it was cooked into a pancake
# 这个就是比较嫩一些
while this one is softer
# 没有说 谁好吃 谁不好吃
I don't think one is better than the other
# 可能说 每个人的口味更偏向于哪一种吧
because everyone has their own preference
# 对
Yep
# 刚才大哥向我们介绍了海蛎煎
That bro just told us that
# 加些甜辣椒会更好吃一些
The "Hai li jian" tastes better with sweet chili sauce
# 然后我们就加了
Then we had a try
# 这个甜辣椒也是我最近刚发现的一个下饭神器
Recently I realized that this sweet chili sauce goes well with rice
# 正如它的名字 甜和辣
As the name goes: sweet and spicy
# 是先有这种甜味 然后又稍微的辣味
Sweetness comes first, followed by very light spiciness
# 但是真的是很下饭
But it goes really well with rice
# 不要忘了告诉大家 我还是很肥美的
Don't forget to tell everyone that I am delicious
# 关灯了
It's time to turn off the light
# 吃完海蛎煎 瞬间感觉
When I just finished my "Hai li jian", I suddenly felt that
# 这个菜市场安静了
The market quieted down
# 关注 雪鱼探店
Subscribe to "Xue yu tan dian"